John Flood

jflood215@gmail.com 802-309-0753 Indianapolis, IN http:jflood215.github.io

https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-flood-developer http://github.com/jflood215

Objective

Dietitian turned developer, looking to utilize an eagerness to learn and a passion for coding to transition into a Full Stack role. I have 10+ years of experience collaborating and communicating on successful teams and look to bring my drive and motivation to this new career.

Technical Skills

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, JSON, REST API's Programming Languages: Javascript, Typescript

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Express.js

Version Control Tools: Git

Run Time Environments: Node.js

Databases: PostgreSQL

Education

Eleven Fifty Academy

Full Stack Web Development Program

Indianapolis, IN

May 2020 – Oct. 2020

24-week immersive learning program for Web Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training.

Virginia Commonwealth University

Dietetic Internship Program

Richmond, VA

SUNY Plattsburgh

B.S. in Nutrition, with a minor in chemistry

Plattsburgh, NY

Technical Projects

- Created a Full Stack macro/calorie calculator and recipe API using React for the front end along with Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL to build the back end. This project is currently deployed on Heroku at: https://macro-recipe-weight-client.herokuapp.com
- Created a responsive website portfolio using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap to showcase my skills to friends, family, and employers. https://jflood215.github.io
- A group project that utilizes Git, Typescript and React legacy code with class components along with Node.js, Express, Material UI and PostgreSQL to develop a Full Stack web app for music lovers. https://theredvinyl.herokuapp.com

Professional Experience

Noom Inc. Remote

Virtual Health Coach

July 2019 – Current

- Met and exceeded all expectations even as company growth exceeded 200% this year.
- Exceptional marks on all performance and transcript reviews.
- Managed a high caseload consistently and efficiently from enrollment to completion.

On Point Nutrition LLC Zionsville, IN

Owner Dec. 2018 – June 2020

- Created detailed and customized nutrition plans that decreased symptoms by up to 60%.
- Quantified and tracked progress through numerous metrics using a data driven approach.
- 88% of initial consults led to a follow up appointment.

Lincare Indianapolis, IN

Senior Medical Nutrition Specialist

Feb. 2009 – July 2019

- Worked as part of the highest grossing, and most successful enteral office in the company.
- Supported and managed multiple dietitians and offices in 6 states around the Midwest.
- Trained over 100 new dietitian hires on all clinical and insurance related aspects of the job.